Guide to the ARS Audiotape Collection ARS.0070
Archive of Recorded Sound
ARS Audiotape Collection
1900-1991
Archive of Recorded Sound
ARS.0070
15 box(es): 419 open reel tapes, 15 audiocassettes, 60 videocassettes
3" reels-5 4" reels-1 5" reels-37 7" reels-334 10.5" reels-40 1/2" tapes on 10" reels - 4 audiocassettes-15 video reels-2 videocassette (VHS)- 59 videocassette (Beta) - 1
Miscellaneous tape recordings, mostly small donations, that span the history of the Archive of Recorded Sound.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Arrangement
Most recordings are described under the series marked "Miscellaneous" according to format and reel size. Some recordings with more distinct provenenance are listed alphabetically by main name or subject associated with it.
Scope and Contents
The ARS Audio Miscellany Collection consists of audio recordings on tape, largely from small donations and with limited documentation and context. Although the archivist may loath the word "miscellaneous," it is an unfortunately necessary descriptor for these kinds of loose ends. Small groups of items, having lost their provenance over time, may not necessarily require the designation of "collection" on their own. So while the title of this constructed collection is ARS Audio Miscellany, the entry points for searching the described items should be sufficient enough on their own to reduce the sting of that awkward name. In a sense, this is a collection that reveals the history of the Archive of Recorded Sound and its role both on the Stanford campus and in the greater community of collectors and researchers of audio recordings. The diversity of content speaks for itself: radio programs, recitals and performances, interviews, actualities, transfers of rare historical recordings, theater production sound effects, even arguably negligible personal recordings (such as "Craig’s Trumpet 6th Grade" and "Clinical Medical Electronics Narration"). Some are transfers of a donor’s originals. Many are stamped Archive of Recorded Sound, or Music Library: these tapes were teaching tools and reserve listening for classes. Among the many fascinating recordings listed here: Martin Luther King speaking at Grace Cathedral in San Francisco less than a week after the last Selby march; King George V's 25th Jubilee Address in 1935, originally recorded on an aluminum disc; Queen Elizabeth Coronation Ceremonies from a local broadcast in 1953; songs of the Berkeley Free Speech Movement; the (unpublished) voices of Albert Schweitzer, Lee De Forest, Dylan Thomas, Ogden Nash, Robert Frost, and Pablo Neruda; Lt. Commander Richard Stratton's POW confession in Vietnam; interviews with the Chicago Seven in 1970; Country Joe and the Fish outakes from the KQED studios in 1967; Emperor Franz Joseph speaking into Poulson’s telegramophone in 1900; Duke Ellington recorded at Basin Street West in 1965 for use in the documentary "Love You Madly;" Marian Anderson in personal recordings made for RCA and in an interview at the United Nations in 1976; President Kennedy speaking with the Nigerian Prime Minister over the first satellite communication in 1963. Spelling has been corrected and expanded when reasonably certain. Brackets have been used for guesses. Also, it is important to note that none of this material has been verified by listening.
The ARS Audiotape Collection consists of audio recordings on tape from small donations with limited documentation and context. In a sense, this group of recordings represents the history of the Archive of Recorded Sound and its role both on the Stanford campus and in the greater community of collectors and researchers. The diversity of content here is beyond a simple listing: radio programs, recitals and performances, interviews, actualities, transfers of rare historical recordings, theater production sound effects, even arguably negligible personal recordings (such as "Craig’s Trumpet 6th Grade" and "Clinical Medical Electronics Narration"). Some are transfers of a donor’s originals which may not exist or be traceable today. Many tapes are stamped Archive of Recorded Sound, or Music Library; these were teaching tools and reserve listening for classes. Unsurprisingly, many tapes are minimally annotated. Spelling has been corrected and expanded when reasonably certain, and brackets have been used for guesses. Also, it is important to note that none of this material has been verified by listening. This finding aid is a work in progress, and tapes will be added or removed as it develops.
Among the many fascinating recordings listed here: Martin Luther King speaking at Grace Cathedral in San Francisco less than a week after the last Selby march; King George V's 25th Jubilee Address in 1935, originally recorded on an aluminum disc; Queen Elizabeth's coronation ceremonies from a local broadcast in 1953; songs of the Berkeley Free Speech Movement; the (unpublished) voices of Albert Schweitzer, Lee De Forest, Dylan Thomas, Ogden Nash, Robert Frost, and Pablo Neruda; Lt. Commander Richard Stratton's POW confession in Vietnam; interviews with the Chicago Seven in 1970; Country Joe and the Fish outakes from the KQED studios in 1967; Emperor Franz Joseph speaking into Poulson’s telegramophone in 1900; Duke Ellington recorded at Basin Street West in 1965 for use in the documentary "Love You Madly;" Marian Anderson in personal recordings made for RCA and in an interview at the United Nations in 1976; President Kennedy speaking with the Nigerian Prime Minister as the first satellite communication in 1963; a series of interviews with early airplane pilots; audio from television specials from Tony Bennett, An-Margret and Nancy Sinatra 1967-1868; Russian Molokan Church Music recorded in Potrero Hill, San Francisco in the early 1950s.
Interviews; Live sound recordings; Radio programs
- 1. Berkeley Free Speech Movement Folksongs, 5 audiotape reel(s)
  Free Speech Movement (Berkeley, Calif.)
  - Barrington Hall, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
  - Dan Paik, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
  - KPFA, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
  - Dusty Miller, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
- 2. Meyer Buck Estate, 4 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  Scope and Contents
  Brahms, Symphony No. 1. Toscanini, NBC Symphony Orchestra; Franck, Symphony in D Minor. Erich Leinsdorf, Robin Hood Dell Orchestra of Philadelphia; Strauss, Don Quixote. Munch, Boston Symphony Orchestra. Gregor Piatigorsky, cellist, Richard Burgin, violinist, Joseph de Pasquale, violist; Sounds in the Round
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  All Scotch 111, recorded two track 7.5 ips. brittleness and curling evident
- 3. Chicago Conspiracy Interviews 1970-03-05, 1970-03-08, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
  Dubs From ACF Media Library. Reel 1: Bobby Seale, Charles Garry, Dave Dellinger, Jerry Rubin, Ronnie Davis, Lee Weiner, Abbie Hoffman, John Froines, Tom Hayden, William Kunstler, Leonard Weinglass. Reel 2: James Kunan, Jane Kennedy, Arlo Guthrie, Renault Robinson, Lee Edmunson, Don Duncan, Norman Mailer, Wesley Pomeroy, Jesse Jackson, Staughton Lynd, Tom Hayden, Country Joe McDonald, Stuart Meacham, Ed Sanders, Paul Krassner, Monsignor Rice, Julian Bond, Jerry Rubin.
  Chicago Seven Trial, Chicago, Ill., 1969-1970
- 4. James Drake donation
  - Maxwell House Showboat (disc transfer), 1933-06-15; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
    Related Materials
    Original broadcast discs held in the Archive of Recorded Sound's Transcription and Instantaneous Disc Collection.
  - Sir Thomas Beecham Society – Master Tapes for WSA-519, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
- 5. Early Aviators, Reels 1-3: Interview with Ernie Smith. Public lecture at Santa Clara University by Arthur Dunning Spearman (1899-1977) about John J. Montgomery., 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15, Box 10)
- 6. Alice Ehlers
  Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981
  - Ehlers Inventions Madison, Wisconsin, 1961-10-16; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
  - Ehlers and Malcolm Hamilton “Works for Two Harpsichords” 1964-03-14, 1964-03-16, 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
- 7. Ethic For Broadcasting, An 1, 2, 4, 6, 9, 10, 11, 1961; 7 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
  Seven programs from a 13-week documentary radio series produced by Mary Ann Cusack at Michigan State University - Oakland. The series features taped interviews with 43 broadcasters, including David Brinkley, Martin Agronsky, David Susskind, Mike Wallace, John Daly and Edward R. Murrow.
  Broadcast journalism
- 8. Gaelic: Peg & Dan’s (3” reel); Jan Toby and Gang (5” reel); Peg & Dan’s, Vancouver 1973-08-28 (7” reel) [anonymous gift, 1998], 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
- 9. from box labeled "Heresy; B. Brecht; F. Hayden; N. Maynard"
  - Brecht “Interview with Mrs L. [Fenchtaranger?] re-recording”, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Unmarked, but with “dictation business” note, 1 audiotape reel(s) and 1 audiocassette (Box 9)
  - Maliky, Explosion, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Cocteau, Les Maries de la tour Eiffel, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Private Lives of the Master Race, 2 audiotape reel(s) (one 5" reel, one 7" reel) (Box 9)
  - University Meeting 1966; Theme from Judgment at Nuremberg, 1966-12-09; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Ibsen, Under Milkwood, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Pirandello Notes, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Clinical Medical Electronics Narration, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - KPFA Finnegan’s Wake; Use of Ballads and Folksong by Joyce (2 shows), 1960-06-12; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Irish mood music?, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Notes for [Auciktet?] Lecture, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - “Xmas Recording,” Porteus, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Murdock and Herman Christmas Morning, 1964; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Office Dictation, 1967; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Hostage rehearsal?, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Sound track? Stardust melodies, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - unmarked, includes “Sound track for [illegible] Tape 1” on UC Berkeley notepaper, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Cal Band rehearsal Big Game Show and Rehearsal of Band for Nancy Wilson, 1967; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Professional Ruminations; Family (all); Baal Blocking, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Ibsen Little Eyolf Preliminary Rambling 1-3, 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Clarence E. Burr, “Tape 4” on UC Berkeley notepaper, 1967-11-30; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - [illegible- Turia T?], 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Banchieri, La Pazzia Senile. Sung by Collegium Musicum of Berkeley, 1965-04-23; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
    Banchieri, Adriano, d. 1634. Pazzia senile
  - Wild duck J. 1+2 End of Essay, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Brand 1 and 2, Etc. Nov.10, Susie and Dachs, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Kindermord #3 T 1+2, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - New Hostage Fall, 1967; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Norman Corwin. On a Note of Triumph, VE Day, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Sound Effects—Feet, Chinese Temple, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Herkules, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Material on Beckett, Heidegger etc., 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Notes for Kindermord + Will, Revised for Bogard, 1964-04-05; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
  - Godard, La Chinoise, 2 videotape reel(s) (Box 9)
    Released in U.S. in 1968, available on DVD. Video reels are 1/2" Scotch 361.
- 10. Carlos Hagen donations (more in other collections, esp. preservation tapes)
  - Carlos Hagen, On Fakery in Sound Recordings (radio program with excerpt from Moran ARSC presentation 1968); CBC radio program on Watergate tapes and editing, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    Related Recordings
    See also Carlos Hagen radio programs in Preservation Master Tape Collection, ARS0097.
  - Ku Klux Klan songs from Louisiana (dubbed from discs); Australian songs, including 13 versions of "Waltzing Matilda." donated by Carlos Hagen, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
- 11. Herbert Hoover recordings
  General
  Removed from Stanford Tape Collection. Stanford-related Hoover material retained in Stanford Collection.
  - Herbert Hoover, Our national policies in this crisis. H.H.10, 1950-12-20; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  - Herbert Hoover; Pope Pius XII, 1941-06-29; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  - Herbert Hoover, Can Europe's children be saved? WOR-Mutual, 1941-10-19; 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  - Speech by G. Sokolsky to Lions Club (H.H. 3a); Speech fragment - "Red Oak"; Will Irwin (H.H. 5); Speech by H. Hoover, "The international situation," 11-19-41 Chicago (H.H. 6); "Shall we send armies to Europe?" Union League Club, Chicago; Speech fragment, pt. 2 (H. Hoover) 2-16-41; closing announcement, piano interlude (H.H. 7), includes message from Pershing, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  - Chauncey McCormick address 1941-06-28 (H.H.8); "Must They Starve?" radio drama narrated by Boake Carter, includes excerpt of Hoover address (H.H. 4); Candid Camera 1941-03-12 (H.H. 3b), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    Existence and Location of Originals
    Possibly copies from Hoover Institution for ARS? (has ARS stamp).
- 12. Martin Luther King at Grace Cathedral, San Francisco
  King, Martin Luther, Jr.
  - Dr. Martin Luther King address at Grace Cathedral [3/28/65], 1965-03-28; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    video exists: “In 1965, as a part of the Festival of Grace, celebrating the 1964 completion and consecration of Grace Cathedral…” (http://www.gracecathedral.org/enrichment/crypt/cry_20021002.shtml) Press conference at Grace probably mis-dated 1964-05-29? (Sunday, Meet The Press?, see calisphere images) after Selma marches in ’65, last one ended 3/25/65
  - Grace Cathedral 1964 [misdated, prob. 3/28/1965?]: Bishop Pike address “Civil Disobedience”; Dean Bartlett (Very Reverend C. Julian Bartlett) address “Redemption or Atonement”, 1965-03-28; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
- 13. KPFA
  KPFA (Radio station: Berkeley, Calif.)
  - KPFA Masters I, IV, V, 1986-06; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 9)
  - Victor Frankl, KPFA, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    Frankl, Victor E. (Viktor Emil)
- 14. KQED
  KQED-TV (Television station: San Francisco, Calif.)
  - Country Joe & The Fish studio recordings: 585 #2 "Who Am I" (take 13) / 590 #1 "McGoo" (4 takes); "McGoo Inst. Only"; "Stookly" (3 takes) / 590 #2 "Fixin’ To Die" (10 takes); "Canada" (2 takes), 1967-07-06; 3 audiotape reel(s) half inch tape (Box 1)
    Country Joe & The Fish, KQED Special Projects, Engineer Hank. Probably related to KQED’s “A Day in the Life of Country Joe and The Fish,” filmed Spring 1967.
    Fish (Musical group)
  - Duke Ellington Basin Street Half-Inch Master #3, 1 audiotape reel(s) half-inch tape (Box 1)
    Most likely, this is a production master of the Duke Ellington band performing at Basin Street West in 1965, recordings of which were used in the production of KQED's Love You Madly documentary on Ellington, which originally aired June, 1967.
    Ellington, Duke
- 15 George Lewis 1955-02-27, 1956-03-25. Donated by Norman Spelman in 1983, 1955-1956; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  Lewis, George
- 16. Marty Marshall donation, 2000
  Separated Materials
  also listed in donation, but not found: SU founders day concert 3/11/62; foothill singers concert at sequoias 1/10/64
  - Herbert B. Nanney Organ recital, Sequoias, 1962-02-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    Organ recital by Professor Herbert B. Nanney, Dedicating the Allen Organ given by relatives and friends of Elizabeth B. Mueser to the Sequoias.
    Nanney, Herbert
  - Craig’s Trumpet 6th Grade, Keith 9th at Pop Pop’s, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
- 17. James Melton Show, NBC. Musical excerpts 1949-02-01, 1949-04-29, 1949-03-12, 1949-08-11, 1949-07-11, 1950-08-27, 1950-04-11, 1950-07-12, 1949-1950; 4 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
  Melton, James
- 18. Moran donations
  - William Moran, The Archivist's Responsibility for Authenticity. ARSC Conference, UCLA, 1968-11; 2 audiotape reel(s) 1 5" reel, 1 7" reel (Box 12)
    Moran, William R.
  - Guglielmo Marconi, “The Story of Wireless” in English from a BBC Recording, and in Italian from Radio Italiana; Thomas Edison, "Let us not forget" speech 1919; First words spoken in a phonograph in 1877, taken from a 1927 film of the 50th anniversary of the phonograph, 1919-1927; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
  - Sarah Bernhardt, Phedre; La Samaritaine. Dubs from G&T discs made 1973 by Moran, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
  - Lee De Forest - In Memoriam (WWJ, Detroit program aired 1961-07-03, three days after his death) / Voice of America (WLWO, Washington, DC 1958-11-30) notes on tape box by Moran, tape donated by Mrs. De Forest, 1958-1961; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - RK/WRM [i.e. Koprowski/Moran] tape. Speech in German, Deutschland. Political? 1940s?, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
  - Melba. Songs my Mother Taught Me (1916); Annie Laurie. With vocal introduction and discussion of playing speeds by Bill Moran (planning for ARS record issue), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    removed from Stanford misc.
- 19. Music Library Association
  - Music Library Association Northern California Chapter, Fall 1976 meeting at UCB. Andrew Imbrie speaks on The Angle of Repose, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  - Artis Wodehouse, "The Evolution of Caruso's Performance Style," joint meeting of Northern and Southern California Chapters of MLA, 1983-04-23; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
- 20. Musicians on Music, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12, Box 14)
  Tape 1 (Box 12): Zinka Milanova, Marian Anderson, Isaac Stern, Maria Callas, Sir Thomas Beecham, Victor Borge, Kathleen Ferrier. Tape 2 (Box 14): Weissenberg, Garden, Landowska, Bonynge. [presentation by Ted Fagan]
- 21. A Nation of Nations, NPR American Issues Radio Forum program 1, 1975-09-06; 6 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
- 22. Pablo Neruda speaking and reading poems at the United Nations, 1972-04-11; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
  Neruda, Pablo
- 23. NLLM&T Recording Studio [from Harold Schmidt Collection, content possibly not as labeled]
  - Tony Bennett TV Special, 1967-08-21; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  - Ann-Margret Special. Bob Hope, Danny Thomas, Carol Burnett (30's Spot), Jack Benny. CBS. Background Noises Courtesy NLLM&T Studio, 1968-12-01; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  - Movin' With Nancy - Nancy Sinatra Special. Lee Hazlewood, Frank Sinatra, Jr., Dean Martin, SAmmy Davis, Jr., Frank Sinatra. Sponsored By Royal Crown. NBC. Background Sound Effects Courtesy of Studio, 1968-05-15; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  - Jazz, An Intimate Art. Louis Armstrong, Dizzy Gillespie, Dave Brubeck, Chartles Lloyd. Bell Telephone Comany, NBC. Background Sound Effects Courtesy of Studio, 1968-04-04; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
- 24. "Opera Mystery Tapes"
  from shelf. All notated with SU (Stanford?)
  - Debussy. Three Preludes For Piano. M-t10 3, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - Delibes. Lakmé, Act 2 SU, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - Donizetti. Lucia Di Lammermoor. Act I. Cimara, Metropolitan Opera, 1950-01-14; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - Gounod. Faust. Acts I and II. Pelletier, Metropolitan Opera, 1949-12-31; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - Purcell. Dido and Aeneas M-t10 8, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - Verdi. Fallstaff Reel 2 [ARS stamp], 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - Wagner. Siegfried/Götterdämmerung SU, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - Wagner. Siegfried Acts 2 and 3 SU, 1951; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - unmarked except for 3/13/49, 3/20/49 SU, 1949-03; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - unmarked except for SH [Standard Hour?] 3/27/49, 4/3/49 SU, 1949; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - unmarked except for 11/20/49, 11/27/49 SU, 1949-11; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - unmarked except for 4/23/50, 4/30/50 SU, 1950-04; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
  - unmarked except for 8/10/52, 8/17/52 SU, 1952-08; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 8)
- 25. Pacifica Radio Awards Concert, Six compositions (technical notes refer to Oliveros), 1962-01-12; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
- 26. Packburn demos
  - Packburn demo tape for the Packburn Audio Noise Suppressor, Models 103 & 303, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  - Packburn demo tape of performance of the Packburn Transient Noise Suppressor, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
- 27. Irwin Parnes, KFAC Luncheon at the Music Center programs, 1967-1986; 2 audiocassette(s)
  Irwin Parnes, International Folk Dance Festival founder and producer, interviewed on four KFAC Luncheon at the Music Center programs on 2 audiocassettes. The tapes, which are scoped dubs from the original recordings, were donated by his son Sam Parnes in 1992.
  Parnes, Irwin
  - Mischa Elman, Irwin Parnes, Thomas Cassidy announcer, 1967-01-27 (Box 11)
    Elman, Mischa
  - 36th Annual International Folk Festival, with Irwin Parnes and Anjani Ambegaokar (Kathak dancer). Martin Workman, announcer, 1983-01-31 (Box 11)
  - Irwin and Joy Parnes, Martin Workman, announcer, 1984-02-27 (Box 11)
  - Irwin Parnes, George Eckert (stage manager), Martin Workman, announcer, 1986-12 (Box 11)
- 28. Plano donations
  - Marian Anderson, personal recordings made at RCA-Victor: "Mr. President and Mrs. Roosevelt" (BS-048618); "Your Majesties" (BS-048619) 1940-03-28; interview at the United Nations for U.N. Day by Don Pringle, 1976-10-24. donated by Gerry Plano in 1977, 1940-1976; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    Anderson, Marian
  - Jimmy Durante And Friends. Radio Broadcasts, Dupe Recording from Discs. Gift of Gerry Plano., 1 audiotape reel(s) pancake (Box 15)
- 29. Poulsen
  - Emperor Franz Joseph and Poulson’s Assistant recorded on Poulsen's Telegraphone, 1900 World's Fair, Paris. (tape copied by Movic Taperecorders, 1959 from original Poulson wire now in Copenhagen Museum), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
  - Prof. Blankensteiner interview at Technologische Werbemuesum, Wein about Poulson’s telegraphone and the Franz Joseph recording (tape copied by Movic Taperecorders, 1959), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
- 30. Radio Moscow
  - Radio Moscow. Tchaikovsky's Sleeping Beauty (Tapes 1-3), 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10, Box 14)
  - Radio Moscow. Popular Soviet songs. 2nd program, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
- 31. Russian Molokan Church Music recorded in Potrero Hill, San Francisco. Donated By Mary Jones in 1995, 1950s; 4 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  Related Collection
  See also recordings made in the late 1930s at the same church in the California Folk Music Project Collection, ARS0094.
- 32. Stanford Music Reserves
  with ARS stamp, Knoll address, no t7 number. possibly for Baller classes? Two have Joan Benson written on them
  - African music (Uganda, Tanzania, Mpangu, Handa-Angola), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - John Amadio, flute, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - Myra Hess, Edwin Fischer, Percy Grainger, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - Liszt and Leschetitzky Pupils, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
- 33. Albert Schweitzer
  - Dr. Albert Schweitzer press conference held during the Goethe Celebration, Aspen, Summer 1949. Donated by John L. Hay 1961, 2 audiotape reel(s) (paper tape) (Box 10)
  - Dub of 1949 Schweitzer tapes, transferred May 1966 by KZSU, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
- 34. The Spice Of Life, Adventures in Good Music with Karl Haas, 1984; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
  Syndicated NPR program, possibly as broadcast on KFAC
- 35. K. Hart Smith Trust donation, 1962; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  Biographical Note
  Smith was the son of George D. Smith and Eleanor Hart.
  Tape 1. Side A: Radio broadcast from the Bohemian Club honoring George D. Smith, owner of the Mark Hopkins Hotel on Nob Hill in San Francisco, CA on the occasion of his retirement and farewell after selling the Mark Hopkins. Well-wishers include Conrad N. Hilton from Los Angeles, Gino Seniorini from Rome, S.W. Thurston from Seattle, and others. Side B: Track 1: Classical piano music, unknown pianist. Track 2: Unknown live stage play. Tape starts while play in progress.